# **Mohamed Afifi**

**E:** drmo.afifi@gmail.com

M: 0414422632

**Unit 306** 

11 Lewis Avenue

Rhodes NSW 2138

## **Career Summary**

I am a pharmacist; I am also training to be a lawyer. I have completed five University degrees and I am currently completing my PhD. I am completing my full-stack development course and will be moving on to a data science course. I wanted to learn code so I can apply my knowledge and ideas in the areas of Medicine and Pharmacy, innovative science and technology and even in the Law.

In my PhD I am conducting research that involves both the University of Technology Sydney (UTS) and Arizona State University (ASU). This research requires deploying surveys and collecting data from both Australia and the United States of America.

Medicine and Pharmacy

Medication reminder app and data science collection for my research with UTS-ASU. I plan to implement what I learn into this research.

I have a good understanding of regulatory affairs in Australia and New Zealand as I have recently completed the Master of Pharmaceutical Medicine at UNSW, majoring in regulatory affairs. I have also worked as a registered pharmacist for over ten years thus I have developed a strong understanding of regulatory affairs within the pharmaceutical industry. Additionally, I completed a summer internship at Aegros, where I demonstrated to be able to work well crossfunctionally and develop productive and collaborative relationships between departments and colleagues. I also held several roles as a paralegal.

#### **Education**

- Juris Doctor/Master of Intellectual Property- University of Technology Sydney (estimated completion 2023)
- · Master of Pharmaceutical Medicine (Regulatory Affairs) University of New South Wales (2020)
- · Master of Pharmacy—University of Canberra (2009)
- · Master of Science Management—University of Technology Sydney (2004)
- · Bachelor of Medical Science (Human Biology)—University of Western Sydney (2003)
- · Bachelor of Science (Immunology & Organic Chemistry)—University of Newcastle (2000)

#### Other Education

- · Cert IV Accounting & Bookkeeping (current)
- · Morris Journalism Academy Free Lance Journalism Course (Current)
- · The Coding Boot Camp at the University of Sydney full stack developer.
- · The Science of Pharmaceutical Compounding 2015

#### **Awards**

Learn to Lead Badge with UNSW 2021

#### Non- Award activities

Moot Court with Piper Alderman 2021

# **Employment History**

## Legal

## HIV/AIDES Legal Centre (HALC) (2021 – 2022)

- · Paralegal
  - o Preparing health waiver applications for Department of Home Affairs
  - o Reviewing contracts of sale
  - Preparing briefs for barristers

## **Pharmaceutical Industry**

# **Quality Assurance Intern, Aegros (2020)**

- · Assisted in monitoring staff training and development standards
- · Primarily assisted with QA of development of Covi-immune vaccine
- · Monitoring temperature fluctuations in vaccine freezers
- · Developing procedures and protocols for sterile areas

## **Community Pharmacy**

#### Pharmacist on Duty (2018-2019)

**Priceline Pharmacy | Wentworth Point (2018 – 2019)** 

**Chemist Warehouse | Brookvale (2018 – 2019)** 

- · Dispensed prescriptions
- · Counselled patients on use of medications
- · Stock inventory control
- · Supervised staff and interns

#### Pharmacy Owner / Manager

#### **Priceless Chemists (2011 – 2018)**

- Pharmacy Management—Manage all aspects of daily business operations for two busy, high volume and fast-paced pharmacies located in a in northwest and central Sydney suburbs and open 15 hours every day:
- Dispense and supervise the preparation of up to 300 prescriptions per day.
- · Manage a team of five Pharmacists and seven Assistant Pharmacists.
- Manage all business operations: patient and customer interaction; financial control; supplier management and negotiation; and Medicare claim requirements.
- · Apply a genuine, compassionate, and hands-on approach to patient and customer welfare.
- · Pharmaceutical Compounding—experienced in the compounding of medications bespoke to patients.

#### **Medical Scientist**

# Douglass Hanly Moir Pathology | Immunochemistry / Cytology Laboratory (2002–2004)

## Sydney Diagnostic Service (SDS) | North Ryde (2001–2002)

- · Pathology Services—provided comprehensive routine and emergency pathology testing in the areas of Immunology and Cytology.
- · Multidisciplinary Services—Performed pathology services on behalf of, and in conjunction with General Practitioners, Medical Specialists, Private Hospitals, Nursing Homes and Community Health Services.
- Medical & Scientific Analysis—Prepared tissue and cellular samples to strict technical standards. Worked with a comprehensive range of pathology equipment. Analysed results and prepared customised pathology reports to assist with patient diagnosis

#### **Academic**

# Academic Tutor / Demonstrator, Medical Science - University of Technology Sydney (UTS) | Medical Science & Immunology (Feb – Dec 2004)

- · Academic Teaching Strategies—Instructed and demonstrated for Anatomy and Physiology (1st and 2nd year students) and Immunology (2nd and 3rd year students) to classes of up to 40 undergraduate students.
- Practical Syllabus Contributions—Supervised practical aspects of laboratory classes and experimentation. Conducted discussion groups with diverse student levels.
  Reviewed and marked exams and assessments.
- · Student Progress—Confirmed students' comprehensive subject understanding and ensured meticulous proficiency as a foundation for future skills within the industry. Impressed upon students the impact and implications of their work.

Additional Tutoring—Tutored students in Biology, Chemistry, Mathematics, Science and Business Studies through Action Coaching (Paddington) and Aurora Coaching College (Auburn)

# Leadership

**Career Discovery Mentoring Program UNSW (2021 – current)** 

Preceptor (2014 - 2017), University of Sydney and University of Tasmania

· Preceptor for Pharmacist Interns for two major Australian universities.

## Referees

Available upon request